languagetrainers.co.uk 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy

_**Data Protection Policy GDPR**_

The Global Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) establishes a law regarding data handling and protection effective May 25th 2018 within the European Union (EU). The GDPR will replace the existing Data Protection Directive (Europe Directive 95/46/EC).

Data protection is a priority for the management of Language Trainers. This policy applies to all personal data processed by Language Trainers.

_**GDPR Definitions of terms**_

Our data protection policy is based on the terms used by the European legislator for the adoption of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Our policy should be comprehensible for the general public, clients and business partners. To ensure this, we would like to mention the terminology used in the policy.

__Personal Data__

Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“data subject”). This information can be name, an identification number, location, email address, bank details, IP address, or more that that directly or indirectly can identify the natural person.

__Data Subject__

Data subject is any identified or identifiable natural person. Our students and teachers.

__Processing__

Processing is any operation which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, organisation, storage, modification, deletion, transportation, use.

__Profiling__

Profiling means any form of automated processing of personal data intended to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a person to analyse or predict aspects concerning that natural person's performance at work, economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, or behavior.

__Data Controller__

Person, organization that determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data, alone or jointly with others.

__Data Processor__

A data processor processes the data on behalf of the data controller.

__Consent__

Consent is any freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject's wishes by which the person, by a statement or by a clear affirmative action, signifies agreement to the processing of personal data.

__Third Party__

A third party is any natural or legal person or any other body other than the data subject, the controller, the processor, and the persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or the processor, are authorized to process the data.

_**Data Protection Principles**_

Language Trainers is committed to processing data in accordance with its responsibilities under the GDPR.

Personal data shall be:

  1. processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner in relation to individuals;
  2. collected for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes; further processing for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes shall not be considered to be incompatible with the initial purposes;
  3. adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they are processed;
  4. accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date; every reasonable step must be taken to ensure that personal data that are inaccurate, having regard to the purposes for which they are processed, are erased or rectified without delay;
  5. kept in a form which permits identification of data subjects for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed; personal data may be stored for longer periods insofar as the personal data will be processed solely for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes subject to implementation of the appropriate technical and organisational measures required by the GDPR in order to safeguard the rights and freedoms of individuals; and
  6. processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data, including protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, using appropriate technical or organisational measures.

**Overview**

This Privacy Policy statement explains the data processing practices of Language Trainers. If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any questions about these practices please contact our Data Controller by e-mail at [datacontroller@LanguageTrainers.com](mailto:datacontroller@languagetrainers.com). 

Our site contains some links to third party sites, which are not subject to this privacy policy. Language Trainers does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content on these sites. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit. 

Information provided by you may be requested from one of our group websites under the Language Trainers brand name, or from one of our sister company sites (with shared ownership and operations).

**Information Collected**  
Personal information is collected by Language Trainers. We collect personally identifiable information about you (your “Personal Data”) through: 

  * The use of inquiry and registration forms.
  * The purchase process when you buy any of our products or services
  * The provision of your details to us either online or offline

Elements of your Data that we collect may include: 

  * First and Last name
  * Job title
  * Company name
  * Home address and phone number
  * Mobile telephone number
  * E-mail address
  * Skype address
  * Social media addresses and nicknames
  * IP address and browser information used when viewing our site
  * Payment details such as credit card information that you supply us to make payments
  * Tracking your use of our site to better develop our sites in accordance with your requirements
  * If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our site, products, offers and marketing strategy, you may choose to set your Web browser to not accept cookies. Further information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your computer can be found on [ _http://www.allaboutcookies.org_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) under the ‘manage cookies’ section.
  * Alternatively go to the help menu within your Internet browser.
  * From time to time we may permit 3rd party companies such as Google Analytics to set cookies on Language Trainers sites for purposes which may include market research, revenue tracking or to improve functionality of the site.

**Use and Disclosure of Personal information**

We use your Data for purposes, which may include: 

  * Providing our customers with a personalized service
  * Processing registrations, enrollments and inquiries
  * Conducting market research surveys
  * Organizing giveaways
  * Measuring interest in and improving our website, products and services
  * Resolving disputes, collecting fees and troubleshooting problems

We use the information you provide when booking a language course to complete that enrollment. We do not share this information with outside parties except

1\. To the extent necessary to complete that enrollment or to provide services where the outside party is acting on our behalf and has no independent right to use the information we provide, or

2\. To successors in title to our business, or

3\. In accordance with legal and regulatory requirements, or

4\. As necessary, in Language Trainers’ sole discretion, to protect the perceived rights, safety and property of Language Trainers, users of our websites, and the public. 

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when Personal Information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.   
We also use information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified): 

  * To build up marketing profiles
  * To aid strategic development
  * To audit usage of the site

**Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Devices**

We use cookies to help personalize your use of our sites. A cookie is a small piece of information which is sent to your computer’s hard drive by the web server so that the website can remember who you are. This information may include information relating to your use of our sites, information about your computer such as the computer’s IP address and browser type, demographic data and, if you arrived at our site via a link from a third party site, the URL of the linking page. If you are a registered user this may include your name and email address for verification purposes. 

We use information from cookies for purposes, which may include: 

  * Identifying returning users and registrants
  * Enabling you to move more easily around our site
  * Tracking your use of our site to better develop our sites in accordance with your requirements
  * If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our site, products, offers and marketing strategy, you may choose to set your Web browser to not accept cookies. Further information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your computer can be found on [ _http://www.allaboutcookies.org_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) under the ‘manage cookies’ section.

Alternatively go to the help menu within your Internet browser. 

From time to time we may permit 3rd party companies to set cookies on Language Trainers sites for purposes which may include market research, revenue tracking or to improve functionality of the site. 

**Security Policy**

Language Trainers has appropriate measures in place to help ensure that our users’ Data is protected against unauthorized access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order to maintain the safety of your personal information.

When personal data is deleted this should be done safely such that the data is irrecoverable.

Appropriate back-up and disaster recovery solutions shall be in place.

**Transfer of Data**

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process personal Data necessarily involves the transmission of Data on an international basis. When we collect personal information from you on our website, we comply with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union.

**Access to Data and Contact info**

You may request a copy or send a correction of the personal information we hold about you by contacting the Data Controller at [datacontroller@languagetrainers.com](mailto:datacontroller@languagetrainers.com) or writing to: 

Data Controller  
Language Trainers

21 Fullwell Ave  
Barkingside

IG6 2HA  
England

We may charge the allowable fee under applicable law for provision of this information. 

**Children Under 13**

This site is not intended for use by persons under thirteen (13) years of age. We do not intentionally collect any information on children under 13 years of age. We will undertake to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has notified us that any such details have been obtained.

_**Rights of the data subject**_

One of the key objectives of the new European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is to ensure the privacy and protection of your personal data.

For this you have the following rights:

_**Right to information**_

You have the right to ask the company for information about what personal data is being processed and the justification for such processing.

_**Right of access**_

You have the right to get access to personal data processed by the company.

_**Right to rectification**_

You have the right to ask for modifications of inaccurate personal data and/or to update your personal information if needed.

_**Right to be forgotten**_

You are entitled to ask us to erase your personal information.

_**Right of restriction**_

You are entitled to request us to restrict the processing of your personal information.

_**Right to data portability**_

You are entitled to ask for personal information you may have submitted to us in a portable format.

_**Right to object**_

To processing your personal data

_**Right to object to automated processing including profiling**_

You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects or affects you.

_**Right to withdraw consent**_

You have the right to withdraw consent on your permission to process your personal information at any time.

_**  
**_You can make a right request to our Data Controller at[datacontroller@languagetrainers.com](mailto:datacontroller@languagetrainers.com)

_**Compliance Certification**_

Our security practices comply with the most widely accepted standards and regulations. We are ISO compliant 9001. Our independent third-party auditors test our controls and provide their reports and opinions — which we share with you whenever possible.

_**Data Breach**_

In the event of a breach of security leading to the accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure of, or access to, personal data, Language Trainers shall promptly evaluate the risk to people’s rights and freedoms and if appropriate report this breach to the ICO (Information Commissioner’s Office) not later than 72 hours after becoming aware of it. The Data processor will also be required to notify our clients without undue delay after first becoming aware of a data breach.
